安菲尔德博巴内罗的气氛。
Bombanero Anfield for atmosphere.
不，来吧。
No, come on.
当你得知尤尔根·克洛普要离开的消息时，感觉如何？
What was it like the morning that you got the news that Jurgen Klopp was going to walk away?
赛季结束。
the end of the season.
我想每个人都感到震惊。
I think everyone was in shock.
他为什么要离开？
Why is he leaving?
世界杯。
The World Cup.
有谁知道今年的世界杯吗？
Is there someone that knows about World Cup this year?
但我不知道赢得一场胜利是什么感觉，亚历克西斯。
I don't know what it's like to win one though, Alexis.
你能告诉我吗？
Could you please tell me?
五百万人走上街头。
Five million people on the streets.
人们过去常常在公交车旁边跑上好几公里。
And people used to run next to the bus for kilometers.
那是我足球生涯中最特别的时刻。
That was the most special moment in my football career.
一定。
for sure.
特伦特·亚历山大-阿诺德、莫·萨拉赫、维吉尔·范戴克，他们的合同显然都到期了。
Trent Alexander-Arnold, Mo Salah, Virgil van Dijk, they're all obviously out of contract.
这是玩家谈论的话题吗？
Is that something that players talk about?
我在亚历克西斯·麦卡利斯特的家里，他
I'm at the home of Alexis McAllister, who
正如你们所知，他是一位世界杯冠军，目前效力于
as you'll all know is a World Cup winner currently playing in the
在阿恩·斯洛特的带领下，利物浦队所向无敌。
all-conquering Liverpool side under Arne Slott.
事实上，我想首先问一下你的名字。
And I want to ask firstly, actually, about your name.
麦卡莱斯特现在有点英国式的感觉，但至少可以肯定
Macalester now that's a kind of bit of British about that but certainly at least
我是苏格兰人，也可能是爱尔兰人。
I'm Scottish about it or possibly Irish as well.
是的。
Yeah.
这是爱尔兰语。
It is Irish.
我不知道为什么很多人认为这是苏格兰的。
I don't know why many, many people think it's Scottish.
嗯，就是一坨屎。
Well, it's muck.
一切都是粪土。
Muck everything is muck.
是的，这实际上是爱尔兰语。
Yeah, it's actually Irish.
几个月或几周前，
And a couple of months or weeks ago,
我收到了爱尔兰家人的来信。
and I received a letter from my family in Ireland.
要求你为他们打球？
Asking you to play for them?
不，不，已经太晚了。
No, no, that's too late.
那就太晚了。
That's too late.
是啊，太晚了。
Yeah, that's too late.
但要求我有一天去那里。
But asking me to go there one day.
是的，我很愿意，我很愿意，但感觉很奇怪，因为
yeah i would love to i would love to and it feels weird because
我25岁了，它现在才来。
I'm 25 and it just came now.
但希望有一天我能去见见我所有的家人。
But hopefully, hopefully one day I can go and meet all of my family.
说到家庭，你有一个非凡的足球家庭，不是吗？
Talking of family, you have a remarkable football family, don't you?
我的意思是，有很多成员继续从事足球事业
I mean, so many members that have gone on to have careers in football
和你的家人谈谈。
Talk to your family.
谁玩过？
Who's played?
是的，对我们来说，足球就是一切。
Yeah, for us, football is everything.
你还有我爸爸，
You have my dad,
和迭戈·马拉多纳一起踢球真是非常幸运的家伙
play football with Diego Maradona exactly so very lucky guy
是的，我爸爸和叔叔都踢足球。
So yeah, my dad and my uncle both play football.
然后我的两个兄弟踢足球。
Then my two brothers play football.
现在，弗朗西斯和凯文其中一人在比利时踢球，另一人在阿根廷踢球。
Now one is playing in Belgium, the other one in Argentina, Francis and Kevin.
所以你有四名球员。
So there you have four players.
我的一位表弟现在正在马来西亚踢球，卢西亚诺。
Then one of my cousins is playing in Malaysia now, Luciano.
当然还有爷爷的
and of course granddad's
也踢足球，不是职业足球，而是踢足球。
play football as well, not professionally, but play football.
是的，足球对我们来说意味着一切，这就是我们踢球的原因，这就是我们的原因
Yeah, football means everything to us and that's why we play and that's why we
我们真的很喜欢玩，你家里有一个凯文·麦卡利斯特
we we really enjoy playing it you've got a kevin mcallister in the family
它是以小鬼当家命名的吗？
Was it named after the Home Alone?
我确信您以前曾被问过这个问题。
I'm sure you've been asked this before.
确实如此。
It actually was.
是的，确实如此。
Yeah, it actually was.
直到他15或16岁的时候他才知道。
And he didn't know until he was 15 or 16.
他基本上是在接受采访，他们问他，
He was basically doing an interview and they asked him,
我们在厨房里听，他在客厅里接受采访。
And we were listening to it in the kitchen, and he was in the living room doing the interview.
所以他说，不，我真的不知道。
So he said, no, I don't really know.
我不这么认为。
I don't think so.
我妈妈就在我旁边，她说，
And my mom was next to me and she was like,
是的，这是因为这部电影，所以就是这样
yes it's because of the because of the film so it was it was
这是一个非常有趣的时刻，但是是的，当他 16 岁时，他发现这是因为
quite a funny funny moment and but yeah when he was 16 he found out that it was because of the of
还有更糟糕的事情有待发现。
There are worse things to find out.
作为一个人长大是什么感觉？
What was it like growing up as a...
阿根廷的一个年轻人。
a youngster in Argentina.
我有机会
I had the possibilities to
去不同的俱乐部踢足球。
to go to different clubs and play football.
和我的两个兄弟在一起总是更容易，因为你让他们
and with my two brothers it was always easier because you have them to
随时随地踢足球。
to play football whenever you want.
你一定是从小到大都在玩的。
You must have been playing growing up.
每天我们都非常享受一起玩耍。
Every day we really enjoy playing together.
所以，是的，我从阿根廷青年队开始。
So, yeah, I started in Argentinos Juniors.
马拉多纳效力的阿根廷大俱乐部。
a big club in Argentina where Maradona play.
像里克尔梅、坎比亚索、索林这样的大牌球员都在那里踢球。
Players like Riquelme, Cambiasso, Sorin, big, big players play there.
所以我们决定去，我们所有人都在那里。
So we decided to go, all of us there.
你也提到了里克尔梅。
You mentioned Riquelme as well.
我认为他在阿根廷被广泛认为是一位非常特别的球员，不是吗？
I think he's widely regarded in Argentina as a very special player, wasn't he?
是的，对我来说，他永远是我的偶像。
Yeah, for me, he was always my idol.
我总是这么说。
I always said that.
他是一位了不起的球员。
He was an amazing player.
他曾经打过10号位。
He used to play as a 10.
然后他去了巴塞罗那
Then he went to Barcelona where at
我认为他没有太多享受。
I think he didn't enjoy much.
为了这个特别的故事，我们将简单地跳转到世界杯。
We'll jump ahead to the World Cup, just briefly, just for this particular story.
旧行政区不是从梅西到路易斯·范加尔的行政区，这是真的吗？
the old borough wasn't it borough um from from messi towards louis van gaal is it true that that
因为梅西也非常尊重里克尔梅，并且不喜欢他受到的对待方式。
because also Messi had a lot of respect for Riquelme and didn't like the way he was treated.
一般情况是这样吗？
Is that generally the case?
这就是他对此做出回应的原因。
And that's why he responded to that.
我不知道。
I'm not sure.
我不能说我不能这么说。
I couldn't say I couldn't say that.
我所知道的是，梅西和里克尔梅的关系非常好，当然，
What I know is that Messi and Riquelme have a very good relationship and of course,
里克尔梅在范加尔的日子并不好过。
Riquelme didn't have a good time with Van Gaal.
玛丽亚也没有。
By Maria neither.
Di Maria neither.
但是……那场比赛是……
But... That game was...
这是一件大事，因为我记得迪布·马丁内斯也说过
was a big one because I remember Dibu Martinez as well saying that
赛前他们聊了很多。
They spoke a lot before the game.
我不知道，感觉就像...
I don't know, it felt like...
他们不尊重我们。
They were not respecting us.
是的，这是一场重要的比赛。
So yeah, it was a big game.
这是一场很好的比赛，因为我们赢了。
It was a nice one because we won it.
在点球大战的最后，这有点可怕，但不是吗，是的，最后两个进球
at the end in penalties it got a bit scary though didn't it yeah two goals right at the end and
然后是休息室里的场景以及一些拳头之类的。
And then the scenes in the dugout and the kind of bit of a fisticuffs and all that.
这与决赛类似，因为我们以 2-0 获胜。
It was similar to the final because we were winning 2-0.
两者之间没有攻击性。
Without the aggressive nature between the two.
是的，和决赛非常相似。
Yeah, very similar to the final.
是的，2-0，然后他们进球了。
So yeah, 2-0 and then they scored.
无中生有的两个进球，只是两个传中。
two goals out of nothing, just with two crosses.
嗯，实际上这是一个任意球。
Well, actually it was a free kick.
实际上，非常聪明的任意球。
Clever free kick, actually.
是的，这是一个很好的。
Yeah, it was a nice one.
但是，是的，之后...
But yeah, after...
在加时赛中，我认为我们再次统治了比赛并在点球大战中获胜，但是
during the extra time I think we dominated the game again and won it on penalties but
这是一个很好的。
It was a nice one.
感觉很好。
It felt nice.
感觉就像一场海滩战争。
It felt like a war on the beach.
作为阿根廷人，我们真的很喜欢它。
And as Argentinians, we really like it.
谈到阿根廷足球的本质，在阿根廷踢球和在英格兰踢球最大的区别是什么？
Talking about that nature of Argentinian football, what's the biggest difference between playing in Argentina and playing in England?
我从阿根廷直奔布莱顿。
I went straight from Argentina to Brighton.
所以对我来说这是一个巨大的改变。
So for me it was a huge change.
以什么方式？
In what way?
我认为最困难的部分是身体方面。
I think that the most difficult part was the physical side.
这里的强度太高了。
here the intensity is too high.
这会让这里的人们感到惊讶，因为
That would surprise people here because
我曾与阿根廷交手过两三次，其中一场非常著名。
I've played against Argentina on two or three occasions and one very famous game.
我想说的一件事是他们非常注重身体素质。
And the one thing I would have said is that they're very physical.
我的意思是，显然才华横溢，但总感觉......
I mean, obviously brilliantly talented, but it always felt...
我和罗明坚之类的人比赛过，布朗。
I played against Ruggieri and people like that, Brown.
我可以向你保证，他们的身体素质非常好。
They were pretty physical, I can assure you.
难道是……
Is that...
不是这样吗？
Not the case?
问题是，我认为在阿根廷，更多的是决斗。
The thing is, I think in Argentina it's more about the duels.
这就是我们放置强度的地方。
That's where we put the intensity.
这是...
And here is...
我不知道，你完成的总距离，最高冲刺距离。
I don't know, the total distance you made, the highest sprint.
我认为这就是区别。
I think that's the difference.
然后当我们进行交易时，我们...
Then when we go to deals, we go...
始终为 100%。
always 100%.
我们不在乎。
We don't care.
所以，是的，在阿根廷，更多的是抢断和诸如此类的事情，但这里的身体素质
So yeah, in Argentina it's more about tackles and these kind of things, but here the physical
是的，跑步方面，游戏的速度。
Yeah, the running aspects, the speed of the game.
你花了一段时间才适应吗？
Did it take you a while to adapt?
是的，是的，确实如此。
Yeah, yeah, it did.
我想说八个月到一年。
I would say eight months to a year.
是的。
Yeah.
当我到达这里时，我没有...
And when I arrived here, I didn't have...
我不知道，身体方面对我来说很重要，但我到达后......
I don't know, the physical aspect was a big thing for me, but I arrived and...
两三周后，新冠疫情开始了。
two or three weeks later, COVID started.
所以我没有...
So I didn't have...
我需要的训练，我想说两个月，因为我们无法训练。
the trainings I needed for, I would say two months because we couldn't train.
那很难吗？
Was that difficult?
因为我想象，因为……
Because I imagine, because...
没有球迷，人们必须分开，而你刚刚来到一个新的国家。
there's no fans, people had to be apart, and you've just come to a new country.
实际上一定是这样的，
That must have actually been,
那太难了。
That was so hard.
这对我来说太难了。
That was so hard for me.
我很幸运，因为我妈妈在英国，所以...
And I was lucky because my mom was in England, so...
我有我的妈妈，她过去常常做饭并做所有的事情
I had my mom and she used to cook and do all the things that
当时我不知道该怎么办。
At that time, I didn't know how to do it.
所以...
So...
那是一件大事。
That was a big thing.
但是，是的，那是一段美好的时光。
But yeah, it was a nice period.
当我们在家无所事事时，无法训练。
when we're at home doing nothing, couldn't train.
然后联赛重新开始，没有球迷感觉不舒服，但是
then the league started again and there was no fans didn't felt right but
就是这样。
It is what it is.
之后，我想...你认为这也影响了你的
After that, I think... Do you think that also affected your
阿根廷人的职业生涯是因为你在很小的时候就踢过几场比赛，然后就出现了新冠疫情，然后你就
Argentinian career because you played a couple of games didn't you when you were very young and then there was COVID and then you
直到世界杯前一年左右才回到球队。
Didn't get back into the side until a year or so before the World Cup.
是的，这是因为科迪，但也是因为我不能，
Yeah, and it was because of Cody, but as well because I couldn't,
嗯，在英格兰得到我想要的比赛时间，正如我所说，这花了我时间
uh get the game time i wanted here in england so as i said it took me
就像一年经常玩一样。
Like a year to play regularly.
您是否有时会想，我不确定我能在这里做到吗？
Were there times you thought, I'm not sure I can do it here?
嗯，有一段时间，或者实际上当我开始打球时，我正要离开。
Well, there was a time that I was or actually when I started playing, I was about to leave.
基本上一月份就快到了
Basically, January was coming
你知道十二月和一月英超联赛有很多比赛，
and you know December and January you have lots of games in the Premier League,
所以我们在布莱顿有很多伤病......
So we had a lot of injuries in Brighton and...
没有选择。
there was no option.
所以经理不得不说，好吧，亚历克西斯，轮到你了。
So the manager had to say, okay, Alexis, it's your turn.
那个时候的波特是吗？
Was that Potter at that time?
那是波特，是的。
That was Potter, yeah.
所以是的，我有机会参加比赛，
So yeah, I had the possibility to play,
几场比赛，进一些球。
a couple of games, score some goals.
我认为经理开始了
And I think the manager started
从那时起我就对我更有信心了。
like had more confidence on me from that time.
那是我开始打球的那一刻，我开始有信心我可以
That was the moment where I started playing and I started feeling confident that I could
我能做到。
I could do it.
我认为这很难。
I think it's difficult.
我也在国外的几个地方踢过球，我想
I've played abroad as well in a couple of places and I think
人们自然而然地假设，踢足球，你只是
There's an automatic assumption that football playing, you just
无论你走到哪里，你都会做同样的事，但当你搬到一个国家去适应不同的语言时，情况就不一定如此了。
you carry on the same everywhere you go, but it's not necessarily like that when you move in country to adapt different language.
你刚来的时候会说英语吗？
Did you speak English when you first arrived?
好吧，我必须祝贺你，你成功地学好了这门语言。
Well, I must congratulate you on how you've managed to learn the language really well.
这很重要，不是吗？
And that's important, isn't it?
感觉自己是一切的一部分。
To feel part of everything.
因为当你听不懂别人在说什么时，你会觉得自己有点像个局外人。
Because you feel a bit like an outsider when you can't understand what anyone else is saying.
是的。
Yeah.
即使是在足球场上。
Even on the football pitch.
是啊，太难了。
Yeah, it was so difficult.
语言是...
The language was...
对我来说这是一件大事，我上了一年半的课，然后又回到了学校
was a big thing for me and i did lessons for a year and a half and back to school
是的，基本上。
Yes, basically.
很好。
It was good.
沟通和建立关系总是很愉快的。
It's always nice to communicate and have relationships.
俱乐部内。
within the club.
所以语言
So language
一开始是一个很大的障碍，然后是文化和天气
was was a big barrier at the at the beginning then the culture the weather
天气，不是吗？
The weather, isn't it?
是的，很漂亮。
Yeah, it's beautiful.
尤其是每年的这个时候，从现在到三月左右。
Especially at this time of year from now until about March.
假设阿根廷的天气有点不同。
So let's say that in Argentina is a bit different in terms of the weather.
但是，是的，我必须学习很多东西。
But yeah, I had to learn a lot of things.
正如我所说，我还年轻。
As I said, I was young.
我不知道如何独自生活。
I didn't know how to live on my own.
所以...
So...
这很艰难。
It was tough.
那是艰难的一年，但在那之后，
It was a tough year, but after that,
我热爱这个国家、这里的人民，我在英格兰感到很受欢迎。
I love the country, the people, and I feel very welcome here in England.
很高兴听到格雷厄姆·波特是什么样的人？
that's good to hear what's Graham Potter like?
他是一位非常好的教练
he's a very good coach
需要时间来构建东西的教练。
coach that needs time to build things.
这是你在切尔西没有得到的。
Which you didn't get at Chelsea.
是的，完全正确。
Yeah, exactly.
这很正常，你知道，在俱乐部里，你没有这样的东西。
And which is normal, you know, in the clubs, you don't have that.
你需要的时间，总是这样。
The time you need, it's always like this.
我觉得...
And I felt...
真的为他感到难过，因为我知道他是一位教练，他是一个人。
really sad for him because I know the coach he is, the human being he is.
尽管我第一年没有参加比赛，但我认为他总是在那里支持我，那就是
Even though I didn't play the first year, I think he was always there to support me and that was
非常重要，所以我真的很感激他，我认为他是一位非常好的教练
really important so I'm really grateful with him and I think he's a very good coach that's
希望我们很快就能在球场上见到他
hopefully we will see him soon on the pitch
布莱顿，这是一家运作良好的俱乐部，不是吗？
It's a very well run club, Brighton, isn't it?
这是一个好的起点吗？
Was that a good place to start?
确实。
Definitely.
是什么让他们如此不同？
What makes them so different?
因为他们的出拳超出了他们的体重，实际上，不是吗？
Because they're punching above their weight, realistically, aren't they?
作为一个足球俱乐部。
As a football club.
他们似乎找到了像你这样的球员，来自世界各地的年轻球员，
They seem to find players like yourself, young players coming through from different parts of the world,
然后将他们出售或保留为团队的一部分。
and then sell them on or keep them as part of their team.
他们不会犯很多错误。
They don't make many mistakes.
嗯，我认为每个人都会关注年轻球员、他们出售的球员或诸如此类的事情，但是
Well, I think everyone looks at the young players, the players they sell or these kind of things, but
我不得不说的是，他们在路易斯·丹克这样的球员中拥有很大的基础。
What I have to say is that they have a big base in players like Louis Dank.
这些对俱乐部非常重要的领导人，丹尼·维尔贝克，
These leaders that are so important for the club, Dani Welbeck,
他已经在那里呆了几年了，他对年轻球员的表现令人惊叹。
He's been there for a couple of years and he was amazing with the young players.
是的，他们带来了这样的球员
Yeah, they bring players that
从数据来看，他们认为自己做得很好。
They think they are good from the data.
他们大量使用数据。
They work a lot with data.
所以...
So...
是的，我想俱乐部里的每个人都知道
Yeah, I think everyone at the club knows
这个角色，我认为，正如我所说，我认为
the role and I think, as I said, I think that
当然，他们在刘易斯敦创建了基地，那么你需要管理者。
the base that they created in Lewistown, of course, then you need the managers.
对阵年轻球员，这并不容易。
to play the young players, which is not easy.
他们似乎仍然在寻找聪明的即将到来的经理。
They still seem to find the clever upcoming managers as well.
是的，完全正确。
Yeah, exactly.
在波尔图之后，他们找到了塞尔维亚人，他……他是什么样的人？
After Porto, they found the Serbi, which... What was he like?
他相当疯狂，相当热情。
He's quite frantic, quite passionate.
是的，他是意大利人。
Yeah, he's Italian.
他是意大利人。
He's Italian.
他是个疯狂的人 他是个疯狂的人 我爱他 我爱他 我认为他是我遇到过的最好的教练
he's a crazy guy he's a crazy guy i love him i love him i think he's the best manager i've ever had
真的吗？
Really?
是的。
Yeah.
在阿根廷我也有像海因茨这样的教练。
And then I have coaches like Heinz as well in Argentina.
所以我有非常好的教练。
And so I have very good coaches.
是什么让 Zerbi 如此特别？
What makes the Zerbi so special?
我认为他对足球的热情。
I think the passion he gives for football.
这很特别，他的想法和战术方面令人惊叹。
That's special and then his idea, his tactical side is amazing.
我不知道该怎么说，但他给你自拍。
I don't know how to say it, but he makes your selfies.
在团队中感觉良好。
feel good in the team.
良好的动机。
Good motivation.
是的，所以自从我见到他的第一天起，他对我来说就很棒，这就是为什么我说他是最好的教练。
Yeah, so since the first day I met him, he was amazing with me and that's why I said he was the best coach.
当你回到布莱顿时，球迷们怎么样？
When you go back to Brighton, how are the fans with you?
惊人的。
Amazing.
他们好吗？
They're good?
他们感谢你为他们所做的一切。
They appreciate what you did for them.
我随利物浦回来过两次……
I came back twice with Liverpool and...
他们对我来说一直都很棒。
They've always been amazing with me.
他们知道我对他们的爱。
They know that the love I have for them.
是的，这对我来说是一个非常特别的地方。
And yeah, it's a really special place for me.
如果像利物浦这样的俱乐部来找他们，他们可能会理解。
And they probably understand if a club like Liverpool comes calling.
很难拒绝它，不是吗？
It's tough to turn that down, isn't it?
当你得到的时候，那是什么样子的？
What was that like when you got...
我不知道。
I don't know.
它是怎么发生的？
How did it happen?
你接到电话了吗？
Did you get a call?
你的agent联系过你吗？
Did your agent get in touch with you?
俱乐部有没有说，我们已经收到了报价？
Did the club say, well, we've had an offer?
效果如何？
How did it work?
是的，首先是和我的经纪人一起。
Yeah, it was with my agent first.
当然，你说利物浦是一家大俱乐部，所以很难说不。
Of course, you said Liverpool is a big club, so it's so hard to say no.
但与此同时，也有
But at the same time, there was
我发布了 Glow，所以一切都变得更容易了。
I released Glow, so everything was a little bit easier, let's say.
我认为球迷们不明白利物浦的到来和存在
And I don't think the fans understand that Liverpool comes and is
这是一家大俱乐部，因为这种事发生在那些去切尔西或……的球员身上。
It's a big club because it happened with players that went to Chelsea or...
其他俱乐部和球迷不喜欢这样。
other clubs and the fans don't like it.
我认为这就是你的生活方式，你知道吗？
I think it's just the way you live, you know?
好吧，球迷们从来不喜欢他们最好的球员离开。
Well, fans never like it when their best players go.
我的意思是，你能理解这一点，不是吗？
I mean, you can understand that, can't you?
作为一名足球运动员，我认为...
As a footballer, I think...
但有时球员会以某种方式离开，这会让他们回去感到不舒服，但这种情况并没有发生在
But sometimes players leave in a certain way that makes it uncomfortable for them to go back, but that didn't happen with
是的，完全正确。
Yeah, exactly.
我认为这就是你的生活方式，你知道。
I think it's the way you live, you know.
正如我所说，有一个解约条款，对我来说这对俱乐部来说更容易。
As I said, there was a release clause and for me it was easier for the club.
但我始终尊重他们。
But I always respect them.
这是最重要的事情，因为我真的很感激他们，这就是我这么做的原因。
And that's the most important thing because I'm really grateful with them and that's why I've done it.
正如我所说，我非常爱他们
as I say I have big love for them
我在那里度过了三年半，非常感谢他们。
I spent three years and a half there, so really grateful for them.
我不想过一种糟糕的生活。
And I didn't want to live in a bad way.
我认为这对每个人来说都是最好的。
I think it was the best for everyone.
走进安菲尔德的大门是什么感觉？
What was it like walking through the doors at Anfield?
如此特别，如此特别，因为它是一家大俱乐部。
So special, so special because it's a big club.
你去过 La Bombonera 吗？
And you've been at La Bombonera?
事实上，我本来想问你，这是我在脑海中计划的问题之一，是为了气氛，是邦巴内罗还是安菲尔德？
I was going to ask you actually, that was one of my questions that I got planned in my head was Bombanero or Anfield for atmosphere?
不，来吧。
Nah, come on.
我和迭戈·马拉多纳一起去过那里，你可能听说过他。
I went there with Diego Maradona, you may have heard of him.
这是最难以置信的气氛。
It was the most unbelievable atmosphere.
我的意思是，他们...
I mean, they...
迭戈是个疯子，他试图挂在阳台上，这很奇怪，但是
nuts man as was Diego he was trying to hang over the balcony bizarre but
是的，这太疯狂了。
Yes, it's crazy.
太疯狂了。
It's crazy.
我认为它们是不同的。
And I think they're different.
两者都很棒。
Both are amazing.
我认为在欧洲，利物浦的球迷是最好的。
And I think in Europe, Liverpool's fans are the best.
我这么说并不是因为我为利物浦效力。
And I'm not saying it because I play for Liverpool.
我知道这很难理解，但我认为他们是最好的或者最好的之一。
I know it's hard to understand it, but I think they are the best or one of the best.
但在阿根廷一切都不同因为在阿根廷我们习惯唱歌
but in Argentina everything is different because in Argentina we are used to sing
歌曲就像整个游戏一样。
songs like the whole game.
所以它创造了一些不同的东西，无论我在这里是否认为它更多
So it creates something different, whether here I think it's more
来自粉丝的反应。
a reactive thing from the fans.
当你进展顺利时，他们就会开始实现目标，有时当你遇到困难时，他们就会开始帮助你
when you're going well they start getting there or sometimes when you're struggling they
是的，完全正确。
Yeah, exactly.
这取决于比赛期间发生的情况，而在阿根廷情况有所不同。
It depends what is happening during the game and in Argentina it's different.
但是，是的，这太难了，因为同时，我从小就支持博卡青年队。
But yeah, it's so hard because at the same time, I support Boca Juniors since I was a kid.
是的，那些在安菲尔德灯光下的夜晚
yeah those nights under the lights at Anfield um
特别是可能是在欧冠比赛的淘汰赛阶段的第二回合。
particularly perhaps in, say, a second leg of how it used to be, well, it will be in the knockout stages of a Champions League game.
那一定是别的东西。
That must be something else.
即使这只是一场英超比赛，但当你走出去时，灯亮了，他们都是......
Even if it's just a Premier League game, but that thing when you walk out, the lights are on, they're all...
你永远不会独行。
You never walk alone.
是的，我真的很期待欧冠第二回合。
Yeah, I'm really looking forward to a second leg of Champions League.
考虑到你在欧冠联赛中的起步，我认为你可能会得到一个。
Given how you started in the Champions League, I think you might get one.
希望希望希望是的但是是的在灯光下很容易
hopefully hopefully hopefully yeah but yeah under the light is easy
我不知道前几天对阵皇马的比赛或者有重要比赛的时候这是否神奇
I don't know if it's magic the other day against Real Madrid or when you have big games
你可以打他们，他们真的在我们后面。
you could hit them and they are really behind us.
我认为他们知道我们需要他们，这对于在球迷和球迷之间建立联系非常重要
I think they know that we need them and that's so important to create that connection between fans and
还有球队，所以是的，我真的很爱他们，也很期待第二回合
and the team, so yeah, I really love them and really looking forward for that second leg
欧冠联赛，希望如此。
in the Champions League, hopefully.
我相信你会的。
I'm sure you will.
那就太棒了。
It'd be amazing.
你在尤尔根·克洛普的带领下开始，现在你有了阿恩·施洛特。
You started under Jurgen Klopp, now you've got Arne Schlott.
首先，尤尔根·克洛普，他是什么？
Firstly, Jurgen Klopp, what was he?
我的意思是，我们都看到他，他也有令人难以置信的热情，有点像德瑟维，但是......
I mean, we all see him, he's got that incredible enthusiasm as well, a little bit like Deservey, but...
并在很长一段时间内在那里做了出色的工作。
and did an amazing job there over a long period of time.
他喜欢打球是为了什么？
What was he like to play for?
从第一天起他就表现得很出色。
He was amazing from the first day.
或者实际上在我签约利物浦之前我和他打过电话
or actually before I signed for Liverpool I had a call with him and
我不知道，从那一刻起我就感觉到我们要做
I don't know, since that moment I could feel that we were going to do
很棒的事情，我真的很享受和他在一起的时光。
great things and I really enjoyed my time with him.
他是否试图将俱乐部卖给你？他是否将自己卖给了你？或者他如何不需要这样做
did he try and sell the club to you did he sell himself to you or how did he he didn't need to
嗯，我知道。
Well, I know.
我想你听说过他。
I suppose you'd heard of him.
但是，是的，我只是想知道他对你说了些什么，真的，为了引诱你——他可能不需要说太多——
But, yeah, I just want to know what he said to you, really, to entice you to – he probably didn't need to say much –
但你可能想要得到保证，你知道，你真的会参加比赛。
But you probably wanted assurances that you really, you know, you were going to play.
不，基本上他说将会有
No, basically he said that there was going to be
球队中场球员的变化。
a change in terms of midfielders for the team.
他希望我成为其中的一部分并且
he wanted me to be part of it and
他将我与他在多特蒙德执教的京多安等球员进行了比较。
and he compared me with players like Gundogan, for example, that he managed in Dortmund.
他说我们有相似的事情，我可以成为球队的重要球员
He said that we had similar things and that I could be an important player for
为了利物浦和他的球队。
for Liverpool and for his team.
所以...
So...
这足以说明我需要去那里，因为
That was enough to say I need to go there because
六个月前，我正处于赢得世界杯的时刻。
I was in a moment where I won the World Cup just six months ago.
我想去一家我有机会赢得奖杯的俱乐部。
I wanted to go to a club that I had the opportunity to win trophies.
我想要...
And I wanted...
去一个让我感觉自己很重要的俱乐部，你知道，在那里我可以感觉到
to go to a club where I could feel important, you know, where I could feel that
我可以在那里有一段历史。
I could have a history there.
是的，这足以告诉自己我想为利物浦效力。
Yeah, that was enough to tell myself that I wanted to play for Liverpool.
作为一名教练和一个人，他喜欢为了什么而踢球？
As a coach and as a person, what was he like to play for?
要求高还是？
Demanding or?
是的，要求很高，要求很高。
Yeah, very demanding, very demanding.
是一个人类。
Was a human being.
他太棒了。
He's amazing.
而我...
And I...
我认为当你是一名教练或一名球员时很难看到这一点
I think it's hard when you are a coach or when you are a player to see that
那部分。
that part.
但我认为，当你是一个好人时，一切都会变得更容易。
But I think when you are a good human being, then everything is easier.
而且他很诚实。
And he was very honest.
每次他需要说实话的时候，他都会说出来。
Every time he needed to say the truth, he said it.
所以这对我来说非常重要。
So that's a really important thing for me.
他总是在我身边支持我，因为
And he was always there for me to support me because
我记得一开始，我们没有六人，所以我必须以
I remember at the beginning, we didn't have a six, so I had to start the season with
打六号。
playing as a six.
你喜欢去哪里玩？
Where do you like to play?
你最喜欢的角色是什么？
What's your favorite role?
呃，这对我来说很难说，但我喜欢这样
uh it's hard for me to say it but i like to be
在中间。
in the middle.
如果我能接触到球，我就会很高兴。
If I'm in contact with the ball, then I'm happy.
所以，是的，上个赛季我从六号位开始，然后......
So, yeah, I started as a six last season and...
人们过去常常抱怨或批评我，但他总是在那里支持我。
People used to complain or criticize a little bit, and he was always there to support me.
并保护我，所以这对我来说是最重要的。
and defend me, so that was the most important thing for me.
每当你收到这样的消息时，早上或下午的感觉如何？
What was it like the morning or afternoon, whenever it was that you got the news that
尤尔根·克洛普打算在赛季结束后离开，他很疯狂，因为他在那里呆的时间不长
Jurgen Klopp was going to walk away at the end of the season he was crazy because he'd not been there that long
不，这太疯狂了，因为我们什么都不知道……
No, and it was crazy because we didn't know anything and...
有一天我去训练
There was a day where I went to training and
通常报告过去是1030、1045
Normally report used to be 1030, 1045
当我在去训练场的路上时
And when I was on my way to a training ground,
我们收到一条消息，说我们 10.30 有一个会议。
We received a message that we had a meeting at 10.30.
所以这很奇怪。
So it was quite weird.
当我到达训练场时，更衣室里我就在萨拉赫旁边，所以我问他，
And when I got to the training ground, I'm next to Salah in the dressing room, so I asked him,
这是怎么回事？
What's going on?
他说经理要走了
And he said the manager is leaving
真的吗？
Really?
你从莫·萨拉赫那里得到消息了吗？
You got the news from Mo Salah?
来自莫·萨拉赫，是的。
From Mo Salah, yeah.
他是一个惊喜。
And he was a surprise.
也许他已经为你提供了第一个帮助。
First assist he's done for you, probably.
可能不是第一个。
Probably not the first.
但这是一个惊喜，因为没有人预料到。
But it was a surprise because no one expected it.
我认为当时我们在联赛中排名第一或第二，所以那是一个美好的时刻。
I think at that time we were first or second in the league, so it was a good moment.
所以没有理由离开。
So there was no reason to leave.
但是，是的，我们开了一次会，基本上他...
But yeah, we had a meeting, basically he...
解释一下或者他说他还活着并且
explain or he said that he was living and
我们只得接受它。
We just had to accept it.
当时的心情如何？
What was the mood like?
我认为每个人都感到震惊，因为没有人预料到这一点。
I think everyone was in shock because no one expected it.
这是主要的事情。
That was the main thing.
他为什么要离开？
Why is he leaving?
但我们知道这是他的决定。
But we understand that it was his decision.
我们真的很尊重它。
We really respected it.
他赢得了做任何他想做的事情的权利。
and he earned the right to do whatever he wanted.
但我们立刻就明白了
But we understood straight away that
我们必须以良好的方式结束这个赛季。
we had to finish the season in a good way.
你认为这对你有影响吗？
Do you think it affected you though?
因为你在最后阶段有点失去球权，但你确实受伤了。
Because you kind of went off the ball towards the end, but you did have injuries.
我认为这对我们没有影响。
I don't think it affected us.
不。
No.
也许这可能是
Maybe that could be the
借口，我们可以责怪他，但我认为这不会影响我们
excuse and we could blame him but I don't think that affected us and
我们最后耗尽了能量
we just ran out of energy at the end and
当你与阿森纳和曼城这样的球队竞争时，你必须处于最佳状态。
When you compete against teams like Arsenal and City, you have to be at your best.
不，我认为尤尔根的离开不会影响我们
No, I don't think Jurgen's departure affected us
但是，当然，这对每个人来说都是一个惊喜。
But, of course, it was a surprise for everyone.
亚历克西斯，你有了一位新经理。
Alexis, you've got a new manager.
阿尼什洛克，他的开始真是太棒了。
Arnishlock, what a start he's made.
因为这一定是非常困难的。
Because it must have been incredibly difficult.
接替尤尔根·克洛普的位置，因为他在足球俱乐部中占据着统治地位
fill in the boots of Jurgen Klopp because he's been so dominant at the football club
在足球俱乐部如此有影响力，在足球俱乐部如此成功，以至于追随他的脚步，但是天哪，这是一个多么好的开始啊。
and so impactful at the football club and so successful at the football club that to follow in his footsteps, but boy, what a start.
是的，我想每个人都认为这会很困难，但阿恩不这么认为。
Yeah, I think everyone thought that it was going to be difficult, but not Arne.
不是阿恩，我想……
Not Arne, I think...
从他来到这里的第一天起，他就非常清楚自己想要什么，并且
since the first day he was he was really clear with the things he wanted and
球场内外。
On and off the pitch.
他立即产生了影响吗？
Did he make an impact immediately?
是的，我会立即说。
Yeah, I would say immediately.
我的意思是，我参加季前赛当然是因为我……
I mean, I was in preseason because of course I had...
赛季结束后的国际比赛日。
international break after the season.
所以我们休息了几天。
So we had a couple of days off.
但当我到达美国后，
But when I arrived to America,
我能听到孩子们的声音，他们对阿恩感到非常高兴。
I could hear the boys and they were so happy with Arne.
他们说这是完全不同的，尤其是在控球方面。
They said it was quite different, especially in possession.
告诉我们怎么做。
Tell us how.
我的意思是，我们已经与 Alan 和 Micah 就这个播客发表了自己的看法。
I mean, we've had our opinions on this podcast with Alan and Micah.
他似乎放慢了速度。
that he seems to slow things down.
不，绝对是。
No, definitely.
它是旧的和新的东西的混合。
It's a mix of the old and certainly something of the new.
在中场进行轮换，似乎需要更多耐心
and kind of rotating in midfield and there seems to be a bit more patience
防守上稍微周到一些。
slightly more thoughtful defensively.
这样可以吗？
Would that be right?
告诉我们您的想法。
Tell us what you think.
是的，我认为最重要的是控球，我们更有耐心。
Yeah, I think the main thing is in possession we are more patient.
防守方面我会说
Defensively, I would say
类似于我们过去对尤尔根所做的事情。
similar to what we used to do with Jurgen.
这也取决于其他球队。
It depends on the other team as well.
所以我们对另一支球队的压力进行了很大的改变。
So we changed a lot the pressing in terms of the other team.
我认为最重要的是控球。
I think the main thing is in possession.
在我们更有耐心的地方，我们有不同的模式和不同的动作
where we are more patient, we have different patterns and different movements to
了解空间在哪里并尝试利用它们。
to understand where the spaces are and try to exploit them.
我认为我们仍在探讨这个想法。
And I think we are still getting into the idea.
你认为他更像是一名战术教练吗？
Do you think he's more of a perhaps tactical coach?
比时钟因为时钟是关于激情不是它高能量加金新闻和是的
than than Clock because Clock was about passion wasn't it high energy Gagin press and yeah
是的，当然。
Yeah, for sure.
这是主要的区别，战术方面。
That's the main difference, the tactical side.
正如我所说，我认为这是为了找到自由人或空间。
As I said, I think it's about finding the free man or the space.
并在控球时尝试进攻并更加耐心。
and try to attack it and be more patient when you have the ball.
它适合你吗？
Does it suit you?
是的，当然。
Yeah, for sure.
我会这么说。
I would say so.
是的，对我来说，这也是不同的，因为这是一个不同的位置。
And yeah, for me, it's different as well because it's a different position.
我们之前说过，上个赛季我打的是六号位。
We spoke before that last season I played as a six.
现在更多的是双六，有时我什至可以打八或十，无论你怎么称呼它。
and now it's more double six or sometimes I could even play as an eight or ten, whatever you want to call it.
你一直有能力在中场角色中发挥多才多艺吗？
Have you always had that ability to be versatile within that midfield role?
或者你学会了吗？
Or have you learnt it?
不，我学会了。
No, I learned.
我学会了。
I learned.
我开始打10号位。
I started playing as a 10.
在阿根廷，通常的系统是四、二、三、一，所以我以前玩过
In Argentina, normally the system is four, two, three, one, so I used to play before
落后于九号位，过去更像是一名进攻者。
behind the nine and used to be more of an attacker.
当我到达布莱顿时，情况发生了变化。
It changed when I arrived to Brighton.
从那一刻起，我想我对这个游戏有了更多的了解和理解。
And since that moment, I think I learned and understood the game a little bit more.
这就是我每天都在尝试的事情，尝试去理解。
And that's what I try every single day, try to understand.
我需要的位置或空间
positions or the spaces I need to
去攻击这种东西。
to attack on this kind of thing.
所以是的，这是我学到的东西，我认为它是
So yeah, it's something that I learned and I think it's
这对一个球员来说确实很重要。
It's really important to a player.
我跟...
I spoke to...
罗德里上周也在播客上，他说了类似的话，他经常思考自己的立场。
Rodri last week, who's also on the podcast, and he was saying similar things that he thinks about his position a lot.
他经常谈论自己的位置，并且会观看所有比赛。
He talks about playing the position a lot and also he watches all the games back.
你看你的比赛吗？
Do you watch your games?
并不真地。
Not really.
我曾经这样做过，但现在我们有很多游戏，有时你需要......
I used to do it, but now that we have a lot of games, sometimes you need...
也是放松的时间。
the time to relax as well.
但不，我真的不看比赛。
But no, I don't really watch the games back.
我认为没有必要，因为在俱乐部我们拥有一切。
I don't think it's necessary because at the club we have everything.
通常是我们观看后的第二天或两天
normally the day after or two days after we watch the
有些事情我们需要改进
some of the things that we need to improve so
如果我有时间，我会这样做，但不是经常这样做。
If I have time I do it, but not very often.
你对利物浦的开局表现感到惊讶吗？
Are you surprised of how well Liverpool have started?
考虑到他们有一个新的负责人，尽管你可以立即看出他知道自己在做什么。
given the fact that they had a new man in charge, even though you could immediately tell that he knew what he was doing.
是的，当然，我前几天也这么说过，就像嗯
yeah for sure for sure and i said it the other day like um
我没想到我们会成为现在的样子，因为
I didn't expect us to be in the place we are now because
因为我认为我们正处于转型期。
because I think we are in a transition.
正如我们之前所说，从尤尔根到阿恩，
As we spoke before, from Jurgen to Arne,
新的想法，不同的事情。
new ideas, different things.
但我认为团队很快就明白了。
But I think the team got it quite quickly.
我们真的很喜欢这个主意。
And we really like the idea.
所以我们喜欢踢足球，我想这就是我们现在所处的位置的原因。
So we enjoy playing this football and I think that's why we are in the place we are.
你提到有时你会扮演两个六号和一个八号。
You mentioned that sometimes you play as two number sixes and there's an eight.
有点转变。
kind of switch around.
主要是格拉文伯格你自己，
It's mainly been Gravenberg, yourself,
还有柯蒂斯·琼斯，不是吗？
and Curtis Jones, hasn't it?
这是如何运作的？
How does that work?
如果你愿意的话，那个新的中场。
That new midfield, if you like.
你在其中感受如何？
How have you felt in it?
现在感觉舒服吗？
Does it feel comfortable now?
是的，对我来说感觉非常好，我想对其他人来说也是如此。
Yeah, for me it feels very good, and I think for the other guys as well.
但是，是的，我们有做任何我们想做的事情的自由。
But yeah, we have the freedom to do whatever we want.
有时，因为有时也需要留在自己的地方
sometimes, because sometimes it's about staying in your place as well
正如我之前所说，空间和诸如此类的东西。
and as I said before, spaces and these kind of things.
但与此同时，我们可以自由地做任何我们想做的事，而且我们确实有像瑞安这样的球员
but at the same time we have the freedom to do whatever we want and we do have players like Ryan
柯蒂斯、多姆、远藤、哈维。
Curtis, Dom, Endo, Harvey.
我们有很多优秀的中场球员。
We have a lot of good midfielders.
你必须给他们这种自由。
You have to give them that freedom.
感觉真的非常好，因为你可以拥有这种联系和那些小传球
It feels really, really good because you can have that connection and those little passes
我们之间，你一定会喜欢的。
between us and you will like it.
我一直认为中场球员，背后有一个领袖对他们来说非常重要。
I always think midfielders, it's very important for them to have a leader behind them.
在维吉尔·范戴克身上，
And in Virgil van Dijk,
他的领导力有多大？
How much of a leader is he?
他在场上发声吗？
Is he vocal on the pitch?
是的。
Yeah.
说了很多，是的，但这很好，很好，是的，因为你需要这样的球员
speaks a lot yeah but that's good that's good yeah because you need you need players like that
他以身作则。
And he leads by the example.
他是莫伊、罗博、艾利森的领袖之一。
He's one of the leaders with Moe, with Robbo, Allison we have.
经验丰富的球员确实可以帮助我们成为更好的球员。
experienced players that really help us to be better players.
然后它们是如此重要，因为
And then they are so important because
例如对阵南安普顿的比赛。
For example, the game against Southampton.
这对我们来说不是一场好比赛。
It wasn't a good game from us.
我们有点挣扎，1-2 输了。
We were struggling a little bit, losing 2-1.
这就是你需要球员挺身而出的时刻。
And that's the moment when you need players to step up.
那是在中场休息时经理说的，
And that was the meeting at halftime where the manager said,
现在我希望看到球员们站出来
now I want to see the players to step up and
维吉尔和安萨拉在下半场打出了精彩的表现。
That was Virgil and Ansala playing an amazing second half.
这就是您需要它们的原因。
That's why you need them.
他们是...
They are...
好人，如果你需要，他们会帮助你，然后在球场上他们会做工作。
good people, they help you if you need and then on the pitch they do the work.
你知道我会问你关于莫·萨拉赫的事。
You knew I was going to ask you about Mo Salah.
我是说...
I mean...
令人难以置信的球员。
Incredible player.
他已经做了这么久了。
He's done it for so long.
他是如此的始终如一，即使在那些可能对他不起作用的日子里，他最终也会得到一个
He's so consistent, even on the days where it's perhaps not working for him, he'll end up with a
某个地方的进球，甚至一次助攻，他是什么样的人，我是说，你坐在他旁边，你在更衣室里说过，我们都知道他作为一名球员是什么样的
a goal from somewhere or even an assist what's he like I mean you sit right next to him you said in the dressing room we all know what he's like as a player
作为一个人是什么样的？
What's it like as a person?
是的，首先，一致性是关键，他证明了这一点。
Yeah, first thing, consistency is key, and he showed it.
太棒了，当你拥有他时，你知道他会取得进球和助攻，
amazing and when you have him you know that he's gonna deliver and get the goals and assists and
你需要的，所以这就是为什么他如此重要。
that you need, so that's why he's so important.
然后在场外他对我们的要求很高
And then off the pitch he demands a lot from
来自他和他的队友。
from him and from his teammates.
所以自从我到达利物浦以来，我想我改变了我的日常生活。
So since I arrived to Liverpool, I think I changed a little bit my routine.
以前我不像现在这么经常去健身房。
before I didn't used to go to the gym as much as now.
那是因为他。
And that's because of him.
是因为你在他旁边换衣服而他的腹肌比你好吗？
Is that because you were changing next to him and he had better abs than you?
还是更适合你的足球？
Or is it more for your football?
是的，就是一个。
Yeah, that's one.
但另一件事是他告诉你，你需要变得专业，你需要去健身房，
thing but the other thing is that he tells you that you need to be professional you need to go to a gym and
或者做这种事情。
or do this kind of thing.
所以，是的，很高兴与他合作
So, yeah, it's a pleasure to work with him and
我认为他确实帮助了周围的球员。
I think he really helps the players around.
事实上，我想要这么做，没有什么特别的原因，只是他是我最喜欢的足球运动员之一，特伦特·亚历山大-阿诺德。
I want to actually, for no particular reason other than he's one of my favourite footballers, Trent Alexander-Arnold.
因为从技术上讲，我认为他是传球者，非常出色。
Because technically, the passer of the ball, I think he's extraordinary.
是的，我认为...
Yeah, I think...
每个人都可以看到他的球技，就像他在控球方面的出色表现一样
Everyone can see the quality like he's amazing on the ball and
我知道有很多关于他防守方面的讨论。
I know there was a lot of talking about his defensive side.
但我认为他也很棒。
But I think he's amazing as well.
所以捍卫这一点。
So defend that.
我问你是有原因的
There's a reason I asked you.
关于这三个人的一点点。
A little bit about those three.
特伦特·亚历山大-阿诺德、莫·萨拉赫、维吉尔·范迪克。
Trent Alexander-Arnold, Mo Salah, Virgil van Dijk.
显然他们的合同都会在赛季结束后到期。
They're all obviously out of contract at the end of the season.
这是球员们在更衣室里谈论的事情吗？
Is that something that players talk about in the dressing room because
你希望他们留下来，不是吗？
you'd want them to stay, wouldn't you?
是的，当然，有很多笑话，但是……
Yeah, of course, there is a lot of jokes, let's say, but...
最后，这是个人的事情，我们将尊重俱乐部、他和他们。
At the end, it's a personal thing and we are going to respect the club and him and them.
无论他们做出什么决定，我们当然希望他们留在我们身边，但是
in whatever decision they they make of course we want them to to stay with us but
正如我所说，这是个人决定，我永远不会实现这一目标。
As I said, it's a personal decision and I would never get there.
你认为你能继续赢得本赛季的联赛冠军吗？
Do you think you can go on to win the league this season?
也许现在还为时过早，但能取得领先真是太好了，不是吗？
It's too early, probably, but it's great to have a lead, isn't it?
是的，现在还早，但我们现在已经有了很大的区别。
Yeah, it is early, but we have a nice difference now.
所以...
So...
是的，当然有可能。
Yeah, it is possible, of course.
可以说，我们在那里，我们是候选人。
And we are there, we are candidates, let's say.
但我们需要继续前进，因为现在还为时过早。
But we need to keep going because it's too early.
还有很多很多的比赛即将到来。
There's many, many games to come.
还有冠军联赛。
have Champions League as well.
所以，是的，我们需要继续工作。
So, yeah, we need to keep working.
继续深入了解阿恩的想法，因为我认为我们还有很多东西需要改进。
keep getting into Arne's idea because I think we have a lot of things to improve.
但我们已经醒来了
yet but we are in a good way to woke up
世界杯。
The World Cup.
如果有人了解世界杯，那就是你。
If there is someone that knows about World Cup, it's you.
但我不知道赢得一场胜利是什么感觉，亚历克西斯。
I don't know what it's like to win one though, Alexis.
你能告诉我吗？
Could you please tell me?
我不知道。
I don't know.
我的意思是，这很神奇。
I mean, it's magical.
太特别了。
It's so special.
喜欢，
Like,
我想我们还是
I think we are still
意识到这意味着什么，因为这并不容易
realizing what it means because it's something that's it's not easy and
我不知道，对我来说最重要的是
I don't know, the most important thing for me was
当我们回到阿根廷时，你可以看到人们的脸。
when we went back to Argentina and you could see people's faces.
那是如此、如此特别。
That was so, so special.
数百万人走上街头。
Millions of people out in the street.
街上有 500 万人，我们乘公共汽车去
There was 5 million people in the streets and we went with the bus and
人们过去常常在公交车旁边跑上好几公里。
And people used to run next to the bus for kilometers.
所以你可以看到人们哭着、微笑着、说了很多话。
So you could see people crying, smiling, saying a lot of things.
当然，那是我足球生涯中最特别的时刻。
That was the most special moment in my football career, for sure.
而且我认为它增加了它，因为我认为除了
And also I think it added to it because I think apart from
显然是法国球迷，或许还有一些罗纳尔多的支持者，
obviously France fans and perhaps some Ronaldo supporters,
我认为世界其他国家真的希望阿根廷获胜。
I think the rest of the world really wanted Argentina to win it.
因为梅西。
because of Messi.
玩家们有这样的感觉吗？
Did it feel like that for the players?
是否感觉你想要的不仅仅是为了自己，
Did it feel like you wanted, not just for yourselves,
但对他来说，因为这可能是他所缺少的一件事。
but for him, because it was the one thing that was perhaps missing.
是的，当然。
Yeah, for sure.
我想所有分享过的人...
I think everyone that shared...
更衣室里莱昂内尔希望他
dressing room with Lionel wanting him to
赢得这届世界杯。
to win this World Cup.
这是一个特殊的场合
It was a special occasion and
他是最好的。
He's the best.
他是有史以来最好的足球运动员。
He's the best footballer ever.
我不同意。
I don't disagree.
我的意思是，我显然和迭戈交手过几次，但我从没想过
I mean, I obviously played against Diego a few times and I never thought
我从来没想过我会说有比迭戈·马拉多纳更好的球员。
I never thought I'd ever say that there was a better player than Diego Maradona.
我觉得从能力上来说，几乎是一样的。
I think ability-wise, almost the same.
惊人的相似。
Amazingly similar.
但你必须把它交给长寿，你必须说迭戈有他的问题。
But you have to give it to the longevity and you have to say that Diego had his issues.
这影响了他的职业生涯，而梅西却没有。
which affected his career, whereas Messi's not.
但我们都知道他作为一名球员有多伟大。
But we all know how great he was as a player.
你同意我的观点，这是有史以来最好的。
And you agree with me that it's the best of all time.
他的领导能力或许让一些人感到惊讶。
His leadership perhaps surprised a few people.
我们都可能在美洲杯比赛之前看过采访
We've all seen the interview perhaps before the Copa America game
在巴西。
in Brazil.
我想世界杯上也可能有类似的事情。
And I assume it was probably a similar thing in the World Cup.
作为一个领导者，他真的出来了不是吗？
He really came out, didn't he, as a leader?
是的，我认为他收到了很多...
Yeah, I think he received a lot of...
来自阿根廷球迷的批评对他来说有多艰难你认为我认为这很难吗
criticism from from fans in Argentina how tough was that for him do you think I think it was tough
我想他从来没有表现出来，但这很艰难，因为
I think he never shows it, but it was tough because
他为国家队付出了一切。
He gave everything for the national team.
他为祖国奉献了一切。
He gave everything for his country.
他进入了决赛，但未能获胜。
And he got to finals that he couldn't win.
当你是最好的球员时，你当然会受到批评，但是
and when you are the best player of course you get the criticism but
他一直都在那里。
He was always there.
他继续前进，继续前进，继续前进。
He kept going, kept going, kept going.
最终他确实做到了。
And at the end he was.
他得到了这份工作，但就领导力而言，我认为他，
he got the work, but in terms of leadership, I think he,
他进步了很多，就像他成长起来一样，他对我们来说是一位了不起的领导者。
He improved it a lot, like he grew into that and he's an amazing leader for us.
他话不多，但当我们真正需要他的时候，他就会说话。
He doesn't speak much, but he speaks when, when we really need him.
所以。
So.
例如，在我们进入球场之前，他总是说话并说
for example before we go into the pitch he always speaks and says
他认为的事情或...
the things that he thinks or...
或者他想要的。
or that he wants.
这对我们来说真的很特别。
And that's really special for us.
但正如我所说，他的领导能力令人惊叹。
But as I said, his leadership is amazing.
这不仅仅是口头上的，更重要的是通过例子。
It's not just by word, but it's more by example.
开始也不太顺利，不是吗？
Didn't start well either, did it?
沙特阿拉伯。
Saudi Arabia.
不，一开始并不顺利。
No, it didn't start well.
这一定是有点震惊。
That must have been a bit of a shock.
是的，确实如此。
Yeah, it was.
是的。
It was.
但我们始终相信自己。
But we always believed in ourselves.
公平地说，比赛结束后我们有大约五到十分钟的时间
To be fair, we had like five or ten minutes after the game where
每个人。
Everyone.
真的很难过，没有人能说话。
was really sad and no one could speak.
但五到十分钟后，我们的领导
But after five or 10 minutes, our leaders
里奥、奥塔门迪这些球员，说出了实话，
Leo, Otamendi, these kind of players, spoke and said the truth like,
这取决于我们，仍然取决于我们。
It was up to us, still up to us.
这并不容易。
It wasn't easy.
但最后，我们战胜了墨西哥。
But then at the end, we got the win against Mexico.
从那时起，一切都变得容易多了。
From that on, everything was much easier.
那一刻显然迪玛利亚也在场。
That was that moment with obviously Di Maria in too.
对于梅西来说，这是一个特殊的时刻，不是吗？
to Messi and it was a special moment, wasn't it?
就像，
It was like,
阿根廷世界杯开始了。
Argentina's World Cup had started.
是的。
Yeah.
我认为那场比赛，上半场，你可以感觉到
I think that game, the first half, you could feel
球迷的紧张，甚至对我们来说，这并不容易。
the nervousness from the fans or even for us, it wasn't easy.
我们在演播室里很紧张，我正在观看那场比赛。
We were nervous in the studio and I was watching that game.
我们在那里。
We were there.
显然，就像世界上大多数人一样，如果英格兰不能的话，我希望阿根廷为梅西赢得冠军。
And obviously, like most of the world, I wanted Argentina to win it for Messi if it couldn't be England.
当然，显然，遗憾的是事实并非如此。
of course, obviously, which sadly it wasn't either.
但让我带你进入决赛。
But let me take you forward to the final.
因为描述一下那天发生的事情。
Because describe what happened on that day.
当天的情况如何？
What's it like on the day?
你还记得吗？
Can you remember it?
你还记得比赛前你的样子吗？
Do you remember what you were like before the game?
你紧张吗？
Were you nervous?
兴奋的？
Excited?
是的，在锻炼期间会发生一些疯狂的事情，因为我通常会
Yeah, during the workout something crazy because I normally get
赛前确实很紧张，但世界杯期间并没有这样的情况发生。
really nervous before the games, but during the World Cup it didn't happen.
我不知道为什么。
I don't know why.
甚至在决赛之前也没有。
Not even before the final.
所以基本上当我们在国家队的时候我们有很多时间休息
and so basically when we when we are with the national team we have a lot of time off like
我们可以做任何我们想做的事
we can do whatever we want
我记得那天晚上我睡了大约 10 个小时。
And I remember that night I slept like 10 hours.
我打赌比赛结束后10个小时你都没有睡觉。
I bet you didn't sleep 10 hours after the game.
不，不，绝对不是。
No, no, for sure not.
但是，是的，晚上10个小时。
But yeah, 10 hours during the night.
然后我们吃了午餐。
Then we had lunch.
午睡和午睡两个半小时
siesta and siesta for two hours and a half and
我简直不敢相信，因为，你知道，你会感到紧张，在最后的、最大的舞台上工作......
I couldn't believe that because, you know, you get nervous, work a final, biggest stage on...
我不知道怎么回事，但在那之前我睡了两个半小时
and I had I don't know how but I slept two two hours and a half before that and
我参加了一场比赛，我想这是因为我真的相信我的......
I went into a game, I think it was because I really trusted my...
我的团队和我的队友们都做得很好。
my team and my teammates to do well.
对于中立者来说，这是一场精彩的决赛。
And it was an amazing final for neutrals.
你发挥了重要作用。
And you played a significant part.
是的，我认为每个人都发挥着作用。
Yeah, I think everyone plays a part.
但那个目标特别在那里？
But that goal in particular there?
多么美妙的举动啊，那是多么美妙的足球啊
what a move what a beautiful bit of football that was
很好。
It was nice.
我认为这是世界杯的最佳进球。
I think it was the best goal of the World Cup.
因为我认为每个人都打一触球的方式。
because of the way I think everyone play one touch.
惊人的反击。
Amazing counter attack.
当然，在迪玛利亚之后，这是一个惊人的进球。
And after Di Maria, of course, an amazing goal.
我感觉真的很好。
I felt really good.
当人们问我时我感觉很好
I felt really good when people asked me
是我玩过的最好的游戏。
was the best game I've ever played.
我总是说最后因为我觉得
I always say the final because I felt
真的很好，我觉得自己对球队很重要。
really good and I felt important for the team.
你说你感觉真的很好。
You said you felt really good.
你正在玩一场游戏，你正在主宰它。
You're playing in a game, you're dominating it.
法国打不过。
France can't get a kick.
他们只是不在其中。
They're just not in it.
然后突然间，你从两个人变成了两个人。
And then suddenly, from two and a lot, you're two-two.
我是说...
I mean...
那时你不可能感觉那么好。
You couldn't have felt that good then.
那一定是这样的，这里到底发生了什么？
That must have been like, what on earth is happening here?
当然，这并不容易。
For sure, it wasn't easy.
当他们打进2-1的比分时
when they score the 2-1,
我不知道。
I don't know.
我对自己还是很有信心的。
I was still confident in ourself.
但在这之后，
But then after this,
均衡器
the equalizer
太难了。
It was so hard.
我想当时大家都很紧张。
I think everyone got nervous at that time.
这并不容易。
It wasn't easy.
但后来...
But then...
再次，就像对阵荷兰一样，我们进入加时赛，我们再次展现了自己的表现。
Again, like against Holland, we went to extra time, we showed again.
然后又发生了。
And then it happened again.
所以我认为，正如你所说，对于中立者来说，这是一场疯狂的游戏。
So it was a crazy game, I think, for neutrals, as you say.
这是最非凡的一场比赛，我认为是我一生中最难忘的一场比赛。
It was the most extraordinary match, I think the most memorable in my lifetime.
我可能参加了有史以来第二场最难忘的比赛，那就是墨西哥 86 四分之一决赛。
I probably played in the second most memorable match of all time, which was Mexico 86, the quarter final.
因为迭戈的两个进球，其中一个是用手进球，显然，其中一个进球可能是有史以来最好的进球。
because of Diego's two goals, one with the hand and obviously one was the best goal probably ever scored.
但为了生活，成为团队的一员，经历情绪的过山车，
But to live that, to be part of the team, to go through that emotional roller coaster,
然后是点球大战。
And then the penalty shootout.
我一直以为你会因为你的守门员而赢得点球大战。
I always thought you'd win a penalty shootout because of your goalkeeper.
因为我在这里不做任何工作。
Because I'm not doing any work out here.
我认为他是今天最好的之一。
I think he's one of the best today.
绝对地。
Absolutely.
你看到他今天的扑救了吗？
Did you see the save he made today?
大约一周前对阵尤文图斯是的
a week or so ago against Juventus yeah
他太棒了。
He was amazing.
我认为他是最好的之一。
I think he's one of the best.
他给我的印象是很有个性。
He strikes me as quite a personality.
人们不喜欢他。
People doesn't like him.
他是屎坑的主人。
He's the master of shithole.
但我认为你需要其中之一。
But I think you need one of these guys.
在你的球队中，你需要获胜，这是其中之一
in your team you need to win it's one of them that
当他们在另一支球队时，你会恨他。
When they are in the other team, you hate him.
但当你的团队中有他时，他...
But when you have him in your team, then he's...
他是最好的球员之一，所以真的为他感到高兴，因为他工作非常努力。
He's one of the best, so really happy for him because he worked really hard.
他踢球有点困难，然后他有机会为阿森纳效力。
he struggled a little bit to play football, then he had the possibility to play for Arsenal.
从那一刻起他就展示了自己的能力
and since that moment he showed what he's capable of so
真的为他感到高兴，因为他也是一个好人。
really happy for him because he's a nice guy as well.
点球大战打得怎么样？
How was the penalty shootout?
公平地说，这再好不过了 是的，公平地说，我在对阵荷兰的比赛中遭受了更多的点球大战
to be fair it couldn't have gone better yeah to be fair I suffer more the penalty shooter against Holland and
这是因为是的，我认为他们错过了第二个和第三个是的
this one because yeah I think they missed the second and the third yeah
所以是的，你可以感觉到我们将成为冠军。
So yeah, you could feel that we were going to become champions.
事情并没有那么糟糕。
It wasn't that bad.
终场哨响，点球大战结束。
Final whistle goes, the end of the penalty shootout.
罚球得分。
The penalty is scored.
你还记得你当时的感受吗？
Can you remember how you felt?
你还记得当时的心情吗？
Do you remember the emotion?
我很震惊。
I was in shock.
我不知道该怎么办。
I didn't know what to do.
我记得我做的第一件事是……
I remember the first thing I did, it was...
看看板凳后面，因为我的家人在那里。
to look at behind the bench because my family was there.
那一定很美。
That must have been beautiful.
那太特别了。
That was so special.
我的家人和一些朋友。
My family and some friends.
他们他们他们留下一切去走
that they they they left everything to go and
决赛时我以为他会说他们还剩五分钟就离开了不不不
there for the final i thought he's gonna say they left with five minutes to go no no no
想象一下，我认为你无法从那场比赛中逃脱，所以
imagine that I don't think you could from that game so
所以，是的，让他们站在看台上观看那场比赛真是太特别了。
So yeah, it was so special to have them in the stands and to watch that game.
是的，只是看着他们然后走路
yeah just looked looked at them and walk and
向裁判表示感谢。
Say thank you to the referees.
我不知道为什么。
I don't know why.
我不知道。
I don't know.
我只是在开玩笑，我不知道该怎么做才能公平
I was just in joke I didn't know what to do to be fair
感觉不太真实是的所以所以是的所以特别
it didn't feel real real yeah so so yeah so so special
斯卡罗尼，他是什么样的人？
Scaloni, what was he like?
我的意思是，他显然做得非常出色，而且他几乎没有输过一场比赛
I mean, he did an amazing job, clearly, and he's hardly lost a game
他在那儿的所有时间里 是的
in all the time that he was there yeah
他是一个了不起的人，当这样的时候一切都会变得更容易。
He's an amazing human being and everything is easier when it's like this.
他在国家和国家队非常困难的时刻带领球队。
He got the team in a really difficult moment for the country and for the national team.
仅次于俄罗斯。
after Russia.
从那一刻起，我认为他明白梅西需要什么。
And since that moment I think he understood what Messi needed.
他需要什么？
What did he need?
他需要良好的防守和能够帮助他的人
He needed a good defense and people who
可以跑去帮他干脏活然后
could run and do the dirty job for him and then
基本上就是把球传给他并为他踢球。
Just pass the ball to him and play for him, basically.
但这并不容易，因为最后
but it's not easy because at the end
我想每个人、每个主帅在斯卡罗尼都尝试过这一点之前也是如此。
I think everyone, every manager that it was before Scaloni tried that as well.
但赢得重大比赛很难。
But it's hard winning major tournaments.
是的。
Yeah.
这很难。
It's hard.
太难了。
It's so hard.
和梅西在同一支球队踢球是什么感觉？
What's it like playing on the same team as Lionel Messi?
一开始，这并不容易，因为，你知道，你会感到紧张，
At the beginning, it wasn't easy because, you know, you get nervous,
你会有点不自在，因为我第一次接触就认识我了，我会一直走，哦。
You get a bit self-conscious because I know me with my first touch, I'd have been going, oh.
天哪，这太尴尬了。
God, this is so embarrassing.
我的意思是，他太好了。
I mean, he's so good.
有这样的程度吗？
Was there a degree of that?
当然，当然。
Sure, for sure.
那是第一个
That was the first
比如说，我不是
face, let's say, and I wasn't
这并不容易。
It wasn't easy.
但是当你遇到那个人并与他交谈时，然后......
But then when you meet the guy and you speak with him, then...
你意识到他只是一个人，他是一个了不起的人
you realize that he's just a human being, that he's an amazing guy and
你只需要在球场上理解他，一切都会变得更容易。
You just need to understand him on the pitch and everything is easier.
我和他在球场上的关系非常好。
I have a really good connection with him on the pitch.
我认为这真的非常重要，因为我打球
And I think that's really, really important because I play
当我看到他所做的事情时我就会感动。
and I move when I see what he does.
所以我对他的动作做出了反应。
So I react to his movement.
甚至在他拿球之前还是当他拿球时？
Even before he's got the ball or when he's got the ball?
不，甚至之前。
No, even before.
我尝试去不同的空间，而不是...
I tried to be in different spaces, not to...
进入他的空间或者因为最后他总是有这样的
into his space or because at the end he's always had like
两三个人围攻他。
two or three guys on him.
所以...
So...
如果有两三个人在场，那么球场上就有一部分是空闲的。
There is a part of the pitch that is free if there is two or three with him.
所以我认为关键在于理解这些事情
So I think it's about understanding those kind of things and that
把球交给他，他会做他想做的和他知道的事情。
Give the ball to him and he will do what he wants and what he knows.
有时，甚至在那届世界杯期间，很多时候，你必须看着他，然后想，哇，他是怎么做到的？
And sometimes, and even during that World Cup, many occasions, you must look at him and go, wow, how does he do that?
即使在我醒来的训练中，得分也很棒，但即使在训练中，如果你
even even training I woke up was score fantastic, but even in training if you
你可以给他任何你想要的通行证。
You can give him whatever pass you want.
他的第一次触球将会令人惊叹。
His first touch will be amazing.
这就是开始。
That's the start.
然后，正如我所说，你做出一个动作，他就会看到。
And then, as I said, you make a movement and he will see it.
他在对阵荷兰的比赛中给莫利纳的传球。
The pass he gave to Molina against Netherlands.
你是怎么建议他的？
How did you suggest him?
你知道我在想什么吗？
Do you know what I was thinking?
我不知道，很抱歉打扰，但是当我看《天使》时，
I don't know, sorry to interrupt, but when I watch Mercy,
他能看到你在看台上看不到的东西。
He sees things that you can't see from the stand.
这几乎就像他在玩游戏一样。
And it's almost like he's playing the game.
这是一种灵魂出窍的体验，他从上方观察自己并拥有整个场地的视野。
as an out of body experience where he's looking at himself from above and has a whole view of the field.
我的意思是，他怎么看这些？
I mean, how does he see those?
你有去他那儿吗？
Do you ever go to him?
你怎么看那张通行证？
How do you see that pass?
不，不是真的，因为人们有时会忘记，不是我们吗？
no not really because that's what people forget sometimes isn't it we we
我们现在沉迷于统计数据。
We're obsessed with stats now.
这是进球和助攻，但不是那样，不是吗？
It's goals and assists, but it's not that, is it?
不是那样的。
It's not that.
这是他在中场线做的一些小事，当他周围有四名球员时，你就会说，哦，他完了。
It's the little things he does on the halfway line when there's four players around him and you go, oh, he's done.
然后他找到了出路。
And then he finds his way out.
我认为足球运动员可能比球迷更期待这一点。
I think footballers look perhaps for more of that than perhaps fans do.
我不知道你怎么想 我认为他有一个
I don't know what do you think I think he's got a
一个神，就像他可以为所欲为。
a god apart, like he can do whatever he wants.
对他来说一切看起来都很容易
everything looks easy for him
困难的是要明白你和他不在同一水平，因为这是事实。
The difficult part is to understand that you are not at the same level as him because that's the truth.
如果你明白这一点并且为他效力，那么一切都会变得更容易。
If you understand that and you play for him, then everything is easier.
我真的很喜欢和他一起玩。
I really enjoy playing with him.
这是我唯一能说的。
That's the only thing I can say.
我真的很幸运，真的很幸运，国家队的每个人都很幸运能和他一起踢球，因为
I'm really lucky and really lucky and everyone on the national team is really lucky to play with him because
不会有像他这样的人。
There won't be anyone like him.
不，我同意。
No, I agree.
当你赢得世界杯时，你对梅西比对自己更满意吗？
When you won the World Cup, were you more pleased with Messi than yourself?
不。
No.
好的。
Good.
抱歉，但是没有。
Sorry, but no.
不，这是正确的答案。
No, it's the right answer.
抱歉，但是没有。
Sorry, but no.
不，这是正确的答案。
No, it's the right answer.
我想我会问这个问题，因为团队对他的反应。
I thought I'd ask the question because the reaction of the team towards him.
我的意思是，每个人都很高兴。
I mean, everyone was pleased.
我认为简单的答案是肯定的，但是......
I think the easy answer would be yes, but...
好像，这是我从小就梦想的事情。
Like, it is what I dreamed since I was a kid.
我想要世界杯。
I want a World Cup.
我们想要继续努力，这感觉棒极了。
we want to work on and it felt amazing.
但首先，因为我，因为
But first, because of me, because of the
我这么多年所做的工作都是因为我的家人为我所做的工作。
the work that I've done for so many years because of the work that my family has done for me.
但是，是的，当然我也为他感到高兴。
But yeah, of course that I was happy for him as well.
这是多么好的结束方式啊。
What a way to finish.
我们赢得了世界杯。
We won a World Cup.
我羡慕你。
I envy you.
我还想对您接受这次采访表示衷心的感谢。
And I also want to say a big thank you for this interview.
这太令人着迷了，亚历克西斯。
It's been fascinating, Alexis.
非常感谢。
Thank you very much.
我给你准备了一份礼物。
I got a present for you.
如你所知，在阿根廷我们喝酒
As you know, in Argentina we drink
比赛。
Matches.
很多比赛。
A lot of matches.
是的。
Yes.
所以基本上...这个伙伴适合我吗？
So basically... Is this mate for me?
不，但这是用马黛茶和草药制成的。
No, but this is made with yerba mate, with herbs.
所以，是的，这是给你的礼物。
So yeah, it's a present for you.
我希望你喜欢它。
I hope you like it.
给你，那个金靴子的人。
There you go, the man with the golden boot.
还有银色麦克风，真是荣幸。
And a silver mic, what an honour.
我们在这里反对它，因为我知道你通常更喜欢袋装薯片而不是罐装饮料。
We're up against it here because I know you normally prefer bags of crisps to cans of drinks.
他们相处得很好，亚历克西斯。
They go well together, Alexis.
不过，我看好我们的机会，所以如果你不喜欢壁炉……
I fancy our chances, though, so if you don't like hearth...
我将穿着内衣参加利物浦的下一场比赛。
I'll play Liverpool's next match in my underwear.
永远不要做出这样的承诺谢谢你谢谢你非常感谢你的到来我希望你喜欢
never make promises like that thank you thank you thank you very much for for coming i hope you liked
一半？
Half?
我做到了。
I did.
上半场和下半场。
First half and second half.
非常感谢。
So thank you very much.
那是一种荣幸。
That's a pleasure.